Contact

the.jeffdoan@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/the-jeff-doan (LinkedIn) hire.jefff.co/ (Personal) myperfectjob.club/ (Other) findnewsletters.com/ (Other)

Top Skills

UX design UI design

Front-end Development

Languages

English

Jeff Doan

Lead Product Designer / Design Manager at Thriveworks Denver, Colorado, United States

Summary

I'm a Denver-based nerd, growth & product designer, front-end tinkerer, and father. I'm also a lover of garage rock, Led Zeppelin vinyls, minivans, Tolkien & Discworld, and my collection of colorful pants. I have 16+ years of UX/UI design, front-end (HTML, CSS & JavaScript) experience, and am dangerous enough when it comes to Ruby/Rails and PHP.

I make products that help people do things they cannot easily do otherwise. I am huge fan of Customer Onboarding and Jobs-to-be-Done as well.

Experience

Thriveworks

Lead Product Designer / Design Manager October 2021 - Present (1 year 6 months)

Denver, Colorado, United States

- Optimizing the mental health journey, and trying to make therapists' lives easier + need less technology
- Lead UX research calls for therapists and clients by understanding their Jobs to be Done
- Designed & validated new tools to streamline therapists daily jobs to increase productivity, satisfaction, and retention

Productboard

Senior Product Designer, Growth

May 2021 - October 2021 (6 months)

Denver, Colorado, United States

- Defined and setup SEO strategy
- Defined continuous research strategy
- Led research and strategy for updated homepage storytelling

SimplePractice

3 years 11 months

Director of Growth Design September 2019 - May 2021 (1 year 9 months)

Greater Denver Area

- Increase trial-to-paid activation rate by 25%
- Manage growth product roadmap to focus on high-impact efforts with limited resources
- Increase visit-to-trial sign up conversion by 9%
- Redesigned, rebuilt, and relaunched simplepractice.com to optimize for conversions
- Manage website team with 2 senior engineers and SEO specialist, to optimize for performance & conversions

Senior Product Designer
July 2017 - September 2019 (2 years 3 months)
Santa Monica, CA

- A mishmash of making the experience better while maintaining key business goals
- Helping define product strategy, writing user stories, and leading UX research

DogVacay Senior UX/UI Designer October 2016 - July 2017 (10 months) Santa Monica, CA

- Search filter persistence: when a guest enters filter criteria, this persists until they change it (even on subsequent site visits)—led to an increase in engagement and conversion
- Desktop geolocation: get specific lat/long of desktop users for better search results—led to an increase in conversion
- Host application flow: reduce UI clutter and focus on conversion goals—led to an increase in high quality hosts and conversion
- Checkout optimizations: simplify UI, reduce confusion by re-ordering form fields—led to an increase in conversion
- Mobile Search Result optimizations: add distance from Host & sort filters based on impact—led to an increase conversions
- Host Review optimizations: simplify UI, reduce confusion by re-ordering form fields—led to an increase in conversion
- New vertical work: researching, prototyping and building custom flows for expanding revenue

Tradesy

Product Designer

January 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 8 months)

Santa Monica, CA

- Mobile web navigation: redesigned and built new navigation to kill the —led to deeper, longer site sessions
- Mobile + tablet signup / login: redesigned and built new pattern for simpler use—led to more conversions
- Self-service: researched, designed and built custom Zendesk integration on tradesy.com via their API—freed up Member Care team to tackle bigger member issues
- Mobile + tablet shopping filters: researched, designed and built new filter patterns
- Promoted Listings: researched, designed, and prototyped first noncommission revenue stream—ongoing effort
- In-app Notifications: designed and built framework for system in-app notifications
- Cookie consolidation: built name/key object cookie support to reduce the number of cookies we use overall
- Built JavaScript controller to handle all inline form validations (Github gist explaining front-end markup)
- Performance improvements: across the board—HTML, CSS and image optimization strategies
- Built personalized email recommendations template / custom image gallery email
- Designed & built personalized mobile web homepage concept

LeagueApps

Lead UX/UI Designer

September 2013 - December 2015 (2 years 4 months)

Washington D.C. Metro Area

- The whole shebang: stakeholder interviews, user testing, usability testing, wireframing, UX & UI design, front-end build & JSP integration
- Designed and built front-end mobile framework for LeagueApps-powered sites (16m+ uniques / year and growing), which works on iOS, Android and Windows
- Designed and built LeagueApps-sent emails work in all email clients & Gmail on mobile

- Redesigned the leagueapps.com marketing site to improve conversions for our unique marketshare rethinking how the SaaS platform sales cycle should be presented to prospects (not launched before I transitioned)

nclud

CSS Developer

July 2011 - September 2013 (2 years 3 months)

- Developed usable, optimized, speedy websites for multiple clients—[some design], front-end coding & templates for Ruby on Rails / Java / WordPress / ExpressionEngine / Codeigniter CMS integrations
- Designed/built Facebook apps
- Led the design & development of mobile-specific template module for our open-source Ruby on Rails CMS: BrowserCMS
- Led card-sorting & conducted user-testing for client sites
- Created HTML prototypes / for IA testing
- Spoke & didn't voice crack at multiple events

Thinkdesign

Senior Interactive Designer

February 2010 - July 2011 (1 year 6 months)

Falls Church, VA

- Developed usable, optimized websites for multiple clients—wireframing, design, front-end coding, and CMS integrations
- Designed and developed HTML emails for national / international campaigns
- —wireframing, design, coding, and testing
- Designed banner ads via animated gifs before it was cool
- Created and implemented client PPC campaigns

Marketing General Incorporated eMarketing Manager

April 2008 - February 2010 (1 year 11 months)

Alexandria, VA

- Developed micro-sites for national campaigns—design, wireframing, and front-end coding
- Developed HTML emails for national / international campaigns—wireframing, design, coding, and testing
- Developed promotional, trigger-based, and newsletter HTML emails
- Designed banner ads via animated gifs before it was cool
- Managed team with senior developer

Sit4Less.com Junior Web Designer February 2005 - April 2008 (3 years 3 months)

Developed email and banner ads for national campaigns wireframing, design, coding, and testing

- Developed landing pages for national and local campaigns

Healthy Back Store Designer February 2005 - April 2008 (3 years 3 months) Springfield, VA

- Developed direct mail for national campaigns
- Designed ROP for national newspaper & magazine publications such as The Washington Post, The San Diego Tribune, The Wall Street Journal, and The Boston Globe
- Worked closely with vendors managing multiple print jobs
- Managed team with junior designer

Rocket9 Design
Junior Graphic Designer
February 2005 - September 2005 (8 months)
Merrifield, VA

- Created t-shirts, retooled website, developed direct mail

Education

James Madison University B.S, Studio Art · (2001 - 2004)